<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.kde.atlantik</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0</project_license>
  <name>Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="ast">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="ia">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxAtlantikxx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">Atlantik</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">Atlantik</name>
  <summary>Monopoly®-like Board Games</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Jocs de taula semblants al Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Jocs de taula semblants al Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Monopoly®-ähnliches Brettspiel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Monopoly®-like Board Games</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Monopoly®-similaj Bretludoj</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Juegos de tablero semejantes al Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Monopoly® stiilis lauamängud</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Monopoly® antzeko mahai-jokoak</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Jeux de plateau de type Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Xogos de taboleiro estilo Monopoly®.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Permainan Papan Seperti Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Giochi da tavolo simili a Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">Monopoly®-ის მსგავსი სამაგიდო თამაშები</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">Monopoly® 형태 보드 게임</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Monopoly®-achtige bordspellen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Gry planszowe rodzaju Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Jogos de Tabuleiro do tipo Monopólio®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Jocuri de table ca Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Doskové hry v štýle Metropoly</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Podobne namizne igre kot Monopoly®</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Monopol®-liknande brädspel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Monopoly® benzeri Masa Oyunları</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Подібні до Monopoly® ігри на дошці</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxMonopoly®-like Board Gamesxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">類似 Monopoly® 的棋盤遊戲</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Atlantik is a KDE client for playing Monopoly®-like board games on the
      monopd network.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">L'Atlantik és un client del KDE per a jugar als jocs de taula semblants al Monopoly® a la xarxa «monopd».</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Atlantik és un client de KDE per a jugar als jocs de taula semblants al Monopoly® en la xarxa «monopd».</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Atlantik ist ein KDE-Programm für Monopoly®-ähnliche Brettspiele im „monopd“-Netzwerk.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Atlantik is a KDE client for playing Monopoly®-like board games on the monopd network.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Atlantik estas KDE-kliento por ludi Monopoly®-similajn tabulludojn en la monopd-reto.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Atlantik es un cliente de KDE para jugar partidas de tipo Monopoly en la red monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Atlantik on KDE klient Monopoly® stiilis lauamängude mängimiseks monopd võrgus.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Atlantik, «monopod» sarean Monopoly® antzeko mahai jokoetara jokatzeko KDEren bezeroa da.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Atlantik est un client KDE permettant de jouer à des jeux de plateau de type Monopoly® sur le réseau monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Atlantik é un cliente de KDE para xogos de taboleiro estilo Monopoly® na rede monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Atlantik adalah sebuah klien KDE untuk memainkan permainan papan seperti Monopoly® pada jaringan monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Atlantik è un client KDE per giocare a giochi da tavolo simili a Monopoly® sulla rete monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">Atlantik -ი KDE-ის კლიენტია Monopoly®-ის მსგავსი სამაგიდო თამაშებისთვის monopd ქსელში.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Atlantik은 monopd 네트워크의 Monopoly® 형태 게임을 플레이하는 KDE 클라이언트입니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Atlantik is een KDE client voor het spelen van Monopoly®-achtige bordspellen op het monopd-netwerk.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Atlantik to klient KDE do grania w gry rodzaju Monopoly® w sieci monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Atlantik é um cliente do KDE para jogar jogos de tabuleiro do tipo Monopólio® na rede 'monopd'.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Atlantik je klient KDE na hranie stolových hier v štýle Monopoly v sieti monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Atlantik je odjemalec KDE za igranje družabnih iger, podobnih kot Monopoly® na omrežju monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Atlantik är en KDE-klient för att spela Monopol®-liknande brädspel på monopd-nätverket.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Atlantik, monopd ağında Monopoly® benzeri masa oyunları oynamak için bir KDE istemcisidir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Atlantik — клієнт KDE для подібної до Monopoly® гри на дошці у мережі monopd.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxAtlantik is a KDE client for playing Monopoly®-like board games on the monopd network.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Atlantik 是來自 KDE 的，在 monopd 網路上遊玩類似 Monopoly® 的棋盤遊戲的用戶端。</p>
    <p>
      Purpose of the Atlantik board game is to acquire land in major cities
      in North America and Europe while being a transatlantic traveler.
      To win the game, players improve monopolized land with profitable
      buildings in the hopes of bankrupting all other players.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">L'objectiu del joc de taula Atlantik és comprar terrenys a les grans ciutats d'Amèrica del Nord i Europa mentre es fan viatges transatlàntics. Per a guanyar la partida, els jugadors cal que millorin els terrenys monopolitzats amb construccions que donin beneficis i amb l'esperança que els altres jugadors facin fallida.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">L'objectiu del joc de taula Atlantik és comprar terrenys a les grans ciutats d'Amèrica del Nord i Europa mentre es fan viatges transatlàntics. Per a guanyar la partida, els jugadors cal que milloren els terrenys monopolitzats amb construccions que donen beneficis i amb l'esperança que els altres jugadors facen fallida.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">In Atlantik muss man als transatlantischer Reisender versuchen, Land in den großen Städten von Nordamerika und Europa zu erwerben. Um das Spiel zu gewinnen, bauen die Spieler profitablen Gebäuden auf Ihrem Land, um damit alle anderen Spieler in den Bankrott zu treiben.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Purpose of the Atlantik board game is to acquire land in major cities in North America and Europe while being a transatlantic traveller. To win the game, players improve monopolised land with profitable buildings in the hopes of bankrupting all other players.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Celo de la Atlantika tabulludo estas akiri teron en gravaj urboj en Nordameriko kaj Eŭropo estante transatlantika vojaĝanto. Por venki en la ludo, ludantoj plibonigas monopoligitan teron kun enspezigaj konstruaĵoj en la espero de bankroto de ĉiuj aliaj ludantoj.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">La finalidad del juego de tablero Atlantik es adquirir terrenos en las ciudades principales de Norteamérica y de Europa mientras viaja en un transatlántico. Para ganar, los jugadores deben mejorar los terrenos monopolizados con edificaciones rentables con la esperanza de llevar a la bancarrota al resto de jugadores.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Lauamängu Atlantik eesmärk on omandada transatlantilise reisimehena valdusi Põhja-Ameerika ja Euroopa suurlinnades. Mängu võitmiseks tuleb mängijatel arendada monopoliseeritud maatükkidel kasutoovaid ehitisi lootuses ajada teised mängijad pankrotti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">«Atlantik» mahai-jokoaren helburua, Ipar Amerikako eta Europako hiri nagusietan lurrak erostea da, atlantikoz haraindi bidaiatze zaren bitartean. Jokoa irabazteko, monopolizatutako lurrak hobetzen dituzten eraikin errentagarriekin, beste jokalari guztiak hondoa jotzera eramateko itxaropenarekin.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">L'objectif du jeu de plateau Atlantik est d'acheter des terrains dans des grandes villes d'Europe et d'Amérique du Nord en devenant un voyageur transatlantique. Pour remporter la partie, les joueurs doivent monopoliser les terrains en installant des bâtiments profitables dans l'optique de provoquer la faillite des autres joueurs.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">O obxectivo do xogo de taboleiro Atlantik é conseguir terras nas principais cidades de América do Norte e Europa como viaxante transatlántico. Para gañar os xogadores deben mellorar as terras monopolizadas con edificios rendíbeis coa esperanza de levar ao resto de xogadores á bancarrota.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Tujuan dari permainan papan Atlantik adalah untuk memperoleh tanah di kota-kota besar di Amerika Utara dan Eropa sambil menjadi pengembara transatlantik. Untuk memenangkan permainan, pemain memperbaiki tanah yang dimonopoli dengan bangunan yang menguntungkan dengan harapan membangkrutkan semua pemain lain.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Lo scopo del gioco da tavolo Atlantik è quello di acquistare delle proprietà nelle principali città dell'Europa e del Nord America, muovendosi come un viaggiatore transatlantico. Per vincere, i giocatori aumentano il valore dei terreni su cui hanno il monopolio: ci costruiscono degli edifici che danno reddito, e sperano di portare gli avversari alla bancarotta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">სამაგიდო თამაშ Atlantik-ის იდეაა ჩრდილო ამერიკაში და ევროპაში დიდი ქალაქების შეძენა მოგზაურობის ხარჯზე. თამაშის მოსაგებად მოთამაშეები აუმჯობესებენ მონოპოლიზებულ მიწას მომგებიანი შენობებით იმედით, რომ სხვა მოთამაშეებს გააკოტრებენ.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Atlantik 보드 게임의 목표는 북아메리카와 유럽 주요 도시에 땅을 사고 대서양을 넘나드는 것입니다. 게임을 이기려면 각 플레이어는 독점권을 얻은 땅에 수익성 건물을 세워 다른 플레이어의 돈을 빨아들여야 합니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Doel van het Atlantik bordspel is om land in grote steden in Noord-Amerika en Europe te verkrijgen terwijl u een trans-Atlantische reiziger bent. Om het spel te winnen, verbetren spelers gmonopoliseerd land met winstgevende gebouwen in de hoop alle andere spelers failliet te laten gaan.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Celem gry planszowej Atlantik jest zdobycie ziem w głównych miastach ameryki północnej i europie, będą podróżnikiem transatlantyckim. Aby wygrać grę, gracze ulepszają swoją ziemię budynkami przynoszącymi zyski z nadzieją, że inni gracze zbankrutują.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O objectivo do jogo de tabuleiro Atlantik é adquirir terrenos nas cidades mais importantes da América do Norte e da Europa, enquanto é um viajante transatlântico. Para ganhar o jogo, os jogadores melhoram nos terrenos monopolizados com edifícios rentáveis, com a esperança de levar os outros jogadores à bancarrota.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Cieľom stolovej hry Atlantik je získať pozemky vo veľkých mestách v Severnej Amerike a Európe a zároveň byť transatlantickým cestovateľom. Aby hráči vyhrali, vylepšujú monopolizovanú pôdu výnosnými budovami v nádeji, že zruinujú všetkých ostatných hráčov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Namen namizne igre Atlantik je da kot kot čezatlantski popotnik pridobiš zemljišča v večjih mestih v Severni Ameriki in Evropi. Za zmago igralci izboljšajo monopolizirano zemljišče z donosnimi zgradbami v upanju, da bodo bankrotirali vsi drugi igralci.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Syftet med brädspelet Atlantik är att förvärva land i större nordamerikanska och europeiska städer, som en transatlantisk resenär. För att vinna spelet förbättrar spelarna monopoliserad mark med lönsamma byggnader med hopp om att göra alla andra spelare bankrutta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Atlantik masa oyununun amacı, uluslararası bir gezgini oynarken Kuzey Amerika ve Avrupa’daki büyük kentlerde arazi satın almaktır. Oyunun kazanmak için, oyuncular diğer oyuncuları iflasa sürükleyebilmek için monopolleştirilmiş arazilerde kâr edebilen binalar dikmelilerdir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Метою гри на дошці Atlantik є накопичення нерухомості у головних містах Північної Америки та Європи. Щоб виграти гру, гравець має забудовувати придбані земельні ділянки прибутковими будинками так, щоб довести до банкрутства інших гравців.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxPurpose of the Atlantik board game is to acquire land in major cities in North America and Europe while being a transatlantic traveler. To win the game, players improve monopolized land with profitable buildings in the hopes of bankrupting all other players.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Atlantik 棋盤遊戲的目的是作為橫跨大西洋的旅者，在北美與歐洲的大城市取得土地。要贏得遊戲，玩家必須用賺錢的建築改善自己所獨有的土地，並期望使其他玩家破產。</p>
    <p>
      All game modes are served by monopd, a dedicated game server designed
      for Atlantik. One of the game modes plays like the popular real estate
      board game known as Monopoly®.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Tots els modes de joc són servits pel «monopd», un servidor de jocs dedicat dissenya per a l'Atlantik. Un dels modes de joc és com el joc de taula de propietats immobiliàries conegut com a Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Tots els modes de joc són servits per «monopd», un servidor de jocs dedicat dissenya per a Atlantik. Un dels modes de joc és com el joc de taula de propietats immobiliàries conegut com a Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Alle Spielmodi werden über monopd gespielt, einem speziellen Spielserver fürAtlantik. Eine der Spielvarianten entspricht dem bekannten und beliebten Brettspiel Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">All game modes are served by monopd, a dedicated game server designed for Atlantik. One of the game modes plays like the popular real estate board game known as Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Ĉiuj ludreĝimoj estas servataj de monopd, diligenta ludservilo desegnita por Atlantik. Unu el la ludreĝimoj ludas kiel la populara tabulludo pri nemoveblaĵoj konata kiel Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Todos los modos de juego están servidos por monopd, un servidor de juego dedicado diseñado por Atlantik. Uno de los modos de juego es similar al del popular juego de tablero de propiedades conocido como Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Kõiki mängurežiime pakub spetsiaalselt Atlantiku jaoks loodud monopd mänguserver. Üks mängurežiim meenutab väga populaarset kinnisvara-lauamängu, mida tuntakse Monopoly® nime all.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Joko-modu guztiak «monopod»ek zerbitzatzen ditu, «Atlantik»erako diseinatutako berariazko zerbitzari bat. Joko-moduetako batek Monopoly® higiezinen mahai joko ezaguna bezala jokatzen da.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Tous les modes de jeu sont proposés par monopd, un serveur de jeu dédié conçu pour Atlantik. L'un des modes de jeu est similaire au jeu de plateau populaire connu sous le nom de Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Todos os modos de xogo sérveos monopd, un servidor de partidas dedicado deseñado para Atlantik. Un dos modos de xogo asimílase ao do popular xogo de taboleiro de propiedade de terras Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Semua mode permainan dilayani oleh monopd, server permainan berdedikasi yang dirancang untuk Atlantik. Salah satu mode permainan dimainkan seperti permainan papan lahan tanah populer yang dikenal sebagai Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Tutte le modalità di gioco sono fornite da monopd, un server di gioco progettato per Atlantik. Una delle modalità di gioco è molto simile a quella di un famoso gioco da tavolo sul mercato immobiliare, noto come Monopoli®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">თამაშის ყველა რეჟიმი კონტროლდება monopd-ის, გამოყოფილი თამაშის სერვერის მიერ, რომელიც Atlantik-ისთვის იქნა დაწერილი. თამაშის ერთ-ერთი რეჟიმია ბინების ყიდვა-გაყიდვის თამაში, რომელიც ცნობილია, როგორც Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">모든 게임 모드는 Atlantik용으로 제작된 독립 게임 서버 monopd에서 제공합니다. 게임 플레이 모드 중에는 유명한 부동산 투자 게임 Monopoly®와 유사한 모드가 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Alle spelmodi worden bediend door monopd, een teogewijde spelserver ontworpen voor Atlantik. Een van de spelmodi speelt zoals het populaire vastgoed bordspel known zoals Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Wszystkie tryby gry są dostarczane przez monopd, serwer gry przeznaczony dla Atlantik. Jeden z trybów gry jest znany z Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Todos os modos de jogo são servidos pelo 'monopd', um servidor de jogos dedicado e desenhado para o Atlantik. Um dos modos de jogo joga-se como o conhecido jogo imobiliário Monopólio®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Všetky herné režimy obsluhuje monopd, špecializovaný herný server určený pre Atlantik. Jeden z herných režimov sa hrá ako populárna stolová hra s nehnuteľnosťami Monopoly.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Za vse načine igre uporablja namenski strežnik za igre monopd, zasnovan za Atlantik. Eden od načinov igre se igra kot priljubljena namizna igra za nepremičnine, znana kot Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Alla speltyper betjänas av monopd, en dedicerad spelserver konstruerad för Atlantik. En av speltyperna spelas som det populära fastighetsspelet känt som Monopol®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Tüm oyun kipleri, Atlantik için tasarlanmış bir oyun sunucusu olan monopd tarafından sunulur. Oyun kiplerinden bir tanesi tam olarak Monopoly® oyununun aynısı gibi oynanır.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Усі режими гри обслуговуються monopd, спеціалізованим ігровим сервером, розробленим для гри в Atlantik. Один з режимів гри подібний до популярної гри на дошці у торгівлю нерухомістю, відомої за назвою Monopoly®.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxAll game modes are served by monopd, a dedicated game server designed for Atlantik. One of the game modes plays like the popular real estate board game known as Monopoly®.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">所有遊戲模式都是由 monopd 所提供，monopd 是設計給 Atlantik 用的專用遊戲伺服器。其中一個遊戲模式與知名大富翁棋盤遊戲 Monopoly® 類似。</p>
  </description>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=atlantik</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://apps.kde.org/atlantik/</url>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.5.1" date="2003-01-02" type="stable"/>
  </releases>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image type="source">https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/atlantik/atlantik.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
    <category>BoardGame</category>
  </categories>
  <provides>
    <binary>atlantik</binary>
  </provides>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.kde.atlantik.desktop</launchable>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-gambling">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
